5 Broken Cameras is a war, documentary film directed by Guy Davidi.
Five broken cameras – and each one has a powerful tale to tell.
Embedded in the bullet-ridden remains of digital technology is the story of Emad Burnat, a farmer from the Palestinian village of Bil’in,
which famously chose nonviolent resistance when the Israeli army encroached upon its land to make room for Jewish colonists.
Emad buys his first camera in 2005 to document the
birth of his fourth son, Gibreel.
Over the course of the film, he becomes the peaceful archivist of an escalating struggle as olive trees are
bulldozed, lives are lost, and a wall is built to segregate burgeoning Israeli settlements.
Himself (Narrator), played by Emad Burnat.
Herself (Emad's wife), played by Soraya Burnat.
Himself (Emad's 4th son), played by Gibreel Burnat.
Himself (Emad's 1st son), played by Mohammed Burnat.
Himself (Emad's 2nd son), played by Yasin Burnat.
Himself (Emad's 3rd son), played by Taki-Ydin Burnat.
5 Broken Cameras (Arabic: خمس كاميرات محطمة, romanized: Khams Kamīrāt Muḥaṭṭamah; Hebrew: חמש מצלמות שבורות, romanized: Hamesh
Matslemot Shvurot) is a 94-minute documentary film co-directed by Palestinian Emad Burnat and Israeli Guy Davidi.
It was shown at film festivals in 2011 and placed in
general release by Kino Lorber in 2012.
5 Broken Cameras is a first-hand account of protests in Bil'in, a West
Bank village affected by the Israeli West Bank barrier.
The documentary was shot almost entirely by Palestinian farmer Emad Burnat, who
bought his first camera in 2005 to record the birth of his youngest son.
In 2009 Israeli co-director Guy Davidi joined the project.
Structured around the destruction of Burnat's cameras, the filmmakers'
collaboration follows one family's evolution over five years of turmoil.
The film won a 2012 Sundance Film Festival award, it won the Golden Apricot  at the 2012 Yerevan International Film Festival,
Armenia, for Best Documentary Film, won the 2013 International Emmy Award, and was nominated for a 2013 Academy Award.
The film explores themes of palestinian-israeli
conflict, palestine, peace, separation, fence.
The tone is dark.